<tutorial>
	<start>start</start>
	<steps>
		<!-- Start -->
		<step>
			<name>start</name>
			<conditions>
				<condition type="WindowVisible">
					<window>Rules</window>
					<next>playerDialog1</next>
				</condition>
			</conditions>
			<text>Welcome to Scorched3D.
This is a short tutorial to help you get to grips with the game.

If the game runs slowly you can adjust the speed of the game in the settings menu accessed via the main game launcher.
<a href="rulesDialog">Click Here to Continue The Tutorial...</a></text>
		</step>
		
		<!-- Rules Dialog -->
		<step>
			<name>rulesDialog</name>
			<conditions>
				<condition type="WindowVisible">
					<window>Rules</window>
					<next>playerDialog1</next>
				</condition>
			</conditions>
			<text>Below is the rules window.
When playing online this window displays any messages from the server.  It can also be used to check what game rules are being used.  

Once you have read the message click the <event action="highlight" window="Rules" control="Ok">Ok</event> button to continue.</text>
		</step>
		
		<!-- Player Dialog -->
		<step>
			<name>playerDialog1</name>
			<conditions>
				<condition type="WindowVisible">
					<window>Team</window>
					<next>game</next>
				</condition>
			</conditions>
			<text>Below is the player setup window.
This window allows you to choose the name, team and tank that your player will use in the game.
<a href="playerDialog2">Click Here to Continue...</a></text>
		</step>
		<step>
			<name>playerDialog2</name>
			<conditions>
				<condition type="WindowVisible">
					<window>Team</window>
					<next>game</next>
				</condition>
			</conditions>
			<text>The <event action="highlight" window="Team" control="Name">name</event> box allows you to enter the name which identifies your tank.  Other players will see this name in game.
Remove the current name by pressing the delete key, and then type in your name using the keyboard.
<a href="playerDialog3">Click Here to Continue...</a></text>
		</step>
		<step>
			<name>playerDialog3</name>
			<conditions>
				<condition type="WindowVisible">
					<window>Team</window>
					<next>game</next>
				</condition>
			</conditions>
			<text>If you have created a game with more than one player you can make some of the players computer controlled by selecting a computer type from the <event action="highlight" window="Team" control="Type">type</event> list.
For the moment, so you can play, please leave this set to Human.
<a href="playerDialog4">Click Here to Continue...</a></text>
		</step>
		<step>
			<name>playerDialog4</name>
			<conditions>
				<condition type="WindowVisible">
					<window>Team</window>
					<next>game</next>
				</condition>
			</conditions>
			<text>The <event action="highlight" window="Team" control="Color">color</event> selection allows you choose the color of your player.
When playing team games it also allows you to choose your team.
Team games and games with more than one player can be created via the custom game setting in the main menu.
<a href="playerDialog5">Click Here to Continue...</a></text>
		</step>
		<step>
			<name>playerDialog5</name>
			<conditions>
				<condition type="WindowVisible">
					<window>Team</window>
					<next>game</next>
				</condition>
			</conditions>
			<text>The <event action="highlight" window="Team" control="Tank">tank</event> selection allows you choose your tank.
This is what your player will look like in the game.
Although each tank looks very different they all share the same weapons and attributes.
<a href="playerDialog6">Click Here to Continue...</a></text>
		</step>
		<step>
			<name>playerDialog6</name>
			<conditions>
				<condition type="WindowVisible">
					<window>Team</window>
					<next>game</next>
				</condition>
			</conditions>
			<text>Once you have given your player a name, color and a tank click the <event action="highlight" window="Team" control="Play">Play</event> button to continue.</text>
		</step>		
		
		<!-- Game -->
		<step>
			<name>game</name>
			<conditions>
				<condition type="FirstMove">
					<next>firing</next>
				</condition>
			</conditions>
			<text>This is the Scorched3D battle arena.  The objective of the game is to destroy all <event action="targets">other tanks</event> in the arena.  The last tank alive wins the round, the tank with the most rounds wins the game.
<a href="game2">Click Here to Continue...</a></text>
		</step>
		
		<step>
			<name>game2</name>
			<conditions>
				<condition type="FirstMove">
					<next>firing</next>
				</condition>
			</conditions>
			<text>Players take it in turns, one by one, to setup defenses and fire their weapons.  It is possible to take turns simultaneously by changing the game settings via the main menu.
<a href="game2b">Click Here to Continue...</a></text>
		</step>
		
		<step>
			<name>game2b</name>
			<conditions>
				<condition type="FirstMove">
					<next>firing</next>
				</condition>
			</conditions>
			<text>You can see the current scores at any time by pressing the S key.  This will also tell you how many rounds are left in the game.
<a href="game3">Click Here to Continue...</a></text>
		</step>
		
		<step>
			<name>game3</name>
			<conditions>
				<condition type="FirstMove">
					<next>firing</next>
				</condition>
			</conditions>
			<text>This is <event action="player">your tank</event>.
Press the 3 key on the keyboard to get a closer look.
The number keys, 0 to 9 on the keyboard, can be used to choose from a set of camera positions.
<a href="game4">Click Here to Continue...</a></text>
		</step>
				
		<step>
			<name>game4</name>
			<conditions>
				<condition type="FirstMove">
					<next>firing</next>
				</condition>
			</conditions>
			<text>The other way to move the camera is with the mouse.
Clicking (or dragging) with the left mouse button on the landscape will move the camera to look at that position.
Clicking and dragging with the right mouse button will rotate the camera.
The mouse wheel controls the zoom of the camera.
<a href="game4a">Click Here to Continue...</a></text>
		</step>
		
		<step>
			<name>game4a</name>
			<conditions>
				<condition type="FirstMove">
					<next>firing</next>
				</condition>
			</conditions>
			<text>It is now time to make move.
The first step is to choose a target, the next step is to choose a weapon and the final step is to aim and fire your tank's gun.
<a href="game4b">Click Here to Continue...</a></text>
		</step>			
		
		<step>
			<name>game4b</name>
			<conditions>
				<condition type="FirstMove">
					<next>firing</next>
				</condition>
			</conditions>
			<text>You can use many different criteria to choose a target.  For example, targets can be chosen by how easy you think they will be to hit, by their current ranking, or even by a how much you dislike them!
<a href="game4c">Click Here to Continue...</a></text>
		</step>	
		
		<step>
			<name>game4c</name>
			<conditions>
				<condition type="FirstMove">
					<next>firing</next>
				</condition>
			</conditions>
			<text>Once your target is chosen you need to select a <event action="highlight" window="Weapon" control="Weapon">weapon</event>.  You can select a weapon by clicking the weapon icon.
When the game starts you only have one type of weapon, you get the chance to buy more weapons in later rounds.  Weapons are bought with money that is earned by killing other players or winning rounds.
<a href="game5">Click Here to Continue...</a></text>
		</step>			
		
		<step>
			<name>game5</name>
			<conditions>
				<condition type="FirstMove">
					<next>firing</next>
				</condition>
			</conditions>
			<text>You aim the tank's gun using the arrow (cursor) keys.
Left and right controls the turret rotation.  Up and down controls the turret elevation.  The + and - keys control the gun's shot power.
<a href="game5a">Click Here to Continue...</a></text>
		</step>		
		
		<step>
			<name>game5a</name>
			<conditions>
				<condition type="FirstMove">
					<next>firing</next>
				</condition>
			</conditions>
			<text>You can speed up all of these adjustments by holding down the Control key.
You can make slower adjustments by holding down the Shift key.
<a href="game6">Click Here to Continue...</a></text>
		</step>			
		
		<step>
			<name>game6</name>
			<conditions>
				<condition type="FirstMove">
					<next>firing</next>
				</condition>
			</conditions>
			<text>An easier way to rotate the tank is to press the A key when the mouse pointer is pointing where you want to aim at.
This will only rotate the tank, the power and elevation adjustments still need to be made manually.
<a href="game7">Click Here to Continue...</a></text>
		</step>		
	
		<step>
			<name>game7</name>
			<conditions>
				<condition type="FirstMove">
					<next>firing</next>
				</condition>
			</conditions>
			<text>When aiming it is always a good idea to take the <event action="highlight" window="Wind" control="Wind">wind</event> (if any) into account.
The wind will blow all shots off target.
<a href="firing">Click Here to Continue...</a></text>
		</step>			
	
		<step>
			<name>firing</name>
			<conditions>
				<condition type="TankDead">
					<next>checkbuying</next>
				</condition>
			</conditions>
			<text>Once you have finished aiming it is time to fire the weapon.  
Usually all players get a turn, however in this tutorial the other tanks will not fire back.

To fire press the space bar.

Keep adjusting your aim and firing until you have killed one of the targets.</text>
		</step>		

    <step>
      <name>checkbuying</name>
      <conditions>
        <condition type="WindowWait">
          <window>Buy</window>
          <next>buying</next>
        </condition>
      </conditions>
      <text>Well done!
The current score is shown below.
We are now starting the next round...</text>
    </step>

    <step>
			<name>buying</name>
			<conditions>
				<condition type="WindowVisible">
					<window>Buy</window>
					<next>defenses</next>
				</condition>
			</conditions>
			<text>To celebrate you have been give a large amount of money to spend.
<a href="buying2">Click Here to Continue...</a></text>		
		</step>	
		
		<step>
			<name>buying2</name>
			<conditions>
				<condition type="WindowVisible">
					<window>Buy</window>
					<next>defenses</next>
				</condition>
			</conditions>
			<text>Below is the buying window.  This window is only shown at the beginning of each new round, so items can only be bought at the beginning of each round.
<a href="buying3">Click Here to Continue...</a></text>		
		</step>		
		
		<step>
			<name>buying3</name>
			<conditions>
				<condition type="WindowVisible">
					<window>Buy</window>
					<next>defenses</next>
				</condition>
			</conditions>
			<text>Click on the green buttons to buy items, and the red buttons to sell items.
You can also buy defenses for your tank by changing to the defense tab.

Once you have bought all you want, or have run out of money click the <event action="highlight" window="" control="Ok">Ok</event> button to continue.</text>
		</step>		
		
		<step>
			<name>defenses</name>
			<text>If you have bought more weapons you can change the current weapon by clicking on the <event action="highlight" window="Weapon" control="Weapon">weapon icon</event> and chosing the weapon from the list.
<a href="defenses2">Click Here to Continue...</a></text>
		</step>			

		<step>
			<name>defenses2</name>
			<text>Shields protect your tank making it harder to kill.  Shields need to be activated to work.
Once activated, the shield absorbs some of the damage your tank would have taken.
If you have bought shields you can activate them by clicking on the <event action="highlight" window="Player" control="Shield">shield icon</event> and choosing the shield from the list.
<a href="defenses3">Click Here to Continue...</a></text>
		</step>			
		
		<step>
			<name>defenses3</name>
			<text>Batteries allow you to recharge your tank's health.  The less health you have, the shorter the distance you can fire.
If you have bought batteries, and have lost some health, you can recharge your health by clicking on the <event action="highlight" window="Player" control="Battery">battery icon</event> and choosing to use some batteries from the list.
<a href="defenses4">Click Here to Continue...</a></text>
		</step>			

		<step>
			<name>defenses4</name>
			<text>Normally your tank will take damage if it falls.  Parachutes stop your tank from taking falling damage.
Once activated, parachutes will be used automatically each time your tank falls.
If you have bought parachutes you can activate them by clicking on the <event action="highlight" window="Player" control="Parachute">parachute icon</event> and turning them on.
<a href="defenses5">Click Here to Continue...</a></text>
		</step>	

		<step>
			<name>defenses5</name>
			<text>Instead of firing tanks can choose to move.  To move a tank needs to have fuel.  The more fuel a tank has the further it can move.
If you have bought fuel you can move by clicking on the <event action="highlight" window="Player" control="Fuel">fuel icon</event>.  Now use the mouse to click on the landscape where you want to move to.
You can only move to the lighter areas of the landscape.
<a href="end">Click Here to Continue...</a></text>
		</step>	
		
		<step>
			<name>end</name>
			<text>This is the end of the tutorial, you can keep playing or quit by choosing exit from the <event action="menu" menu="Player">main menu</event>.
<a href="exit">Click Here to Continue...</a></text>
		</step>		
	</steps>
</tutorial>
